concureworkplace.com 2010-11-21

# Concur Technologies, Inc. Privacy Policy | Concur.com

**NOTICE OF CHANGES to Concur.com visitors: Concur has made changes to its privacy policy in an effort to better describe how it collects, uses, and shares its information. Please contact us by emailing by emailing[concurnews@concur.com](mailto:concurnews@concur.com) with any questions or concerns about these changes.**

Last Updated: October 26, 2010

This Policy explains how your personal information is collected, used, and disclosed by Concur Technologies, Inc. ("Concur") and its subsidiaries and affiliated companies ("Concur" or "We"). This privacy policy ("Policy") applies to the Web sites of Concur, including concur.com and concurbreeze.com (collectively, "Sites"). The Sites are hosted in the United States of America and the personal information you submit to them will be held and processed in the United States of America. If you are based in the European Union, the United States of America does not have equivalent legal protection for personal information as the EU's privacy directive, but nonetheless Concur will treat and protect your information as set out in this privacy policy.

## INFORMATION COLLECTED

We collect information from you in various ways when you use our Sites. We collect information you directly provide to us. For example, we collect your name, email address, postal address, phone number, fax number, demographics, preference information and other information you provide us on our Sites. We also collect credit card numbers if you purchase services on our Sites or use services that reconcile your credit card charges. We may also obtain information from other sources and combine that with information we collect on our Sites.

When you visit our Sites, some information is automatically collected. For example, when you visit our Sites your computer's operating system, Internet Protocol (IP) address, access times, browser type and language, and referring Web site addresses are logged automatically. We also collect information about your usage and activity on our Sites. 

**Cookies.** We may automatically collect information using "cookies." Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive by a Web site. Among other things, cookies help us improve our Sites and your experience. We use cookies to see which areas and features are popular and to count visits to our Sites. If you set your browser not to accept cookies or if you reject a cookie (your help screen or manual should tell you how to do this), it may affect certain features or services of our Sites. 

**Web Beacons.** We may collect information using Web beacons. Web beacons are electronic images that may be used on our Sites or in our emails. We use Web beacons to deliver cookies, count visits, understand usage and campaign effectiveness and to tell if an email has been opened and acted upon.

**Third Party Advertisements** We may also use third parties to serve ads on the Site. Certain third parties may automatically collect information about your visits to this and other Web sites, your IP address, your ISP, the browser you use to visit our Site (but not your name, address, email address or telephone number). They do this using cookies, clear gifs or other technologies. Information collected may be used, among other things, to deliver advertising targeted to your interests and to better understand the usage and visitation of our Site and the other sites tracked by these third parties. This policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, cookies or clear gifs in third party ads, and we encourage you to check the privacy policies of advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of cookies and other technology. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here: [ http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp)

## USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We use personal information collected through our Sites for purposes described in this Policy or disclosed to you on our Sites or in connection with our services. For example, we may use your information to:

  * operate and improve our Sites and services;
  * process and deliver contest entries and rewards;
  * respond to your comments and questions and provide customer service;
  * provide and deliver products and to send you related information, including confirmations, invoices, technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;
  * register you for events and training;
  * communicate with you about new contests, promotions and rewards, upcoming events, and other news about products and services offered by Concur and our selected partners;
  * link or combine with other personal information we get from third parties, to help understand your needs and provide you with better service. 

Concur may store and process personal information in the United States and other countries. 

## SHARING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

We do not share your personal information with third parties other than as follows:

  * in an aggregated form that does not directly identify you;
  * with your consent, for example, when you agree to our sharing your information with other third parties for their own marketing uses subject to their privacy policies;
  * with your employer if you are participating in a Concur service provided through your employer;
  * with third party vendors, consultants and other service providers who are working on our behalf and need access to your information to carry out their work for us;
  * to (i) comply with laws or to respond to lawful requests and legal process, (ii) to protect the rights and property of Concur our agents, members, and others including to enforce our agreements, policies and terms of use or (iii) in an emergency to protect the personal safety of Concur, its customers, or any person;
  * in connection with any merger, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business to another company.

## SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Concur takes reasonable measures to protect your personal information in an effort to prevent loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. 

## YOUR INFORMATION CHOICES AND CHANGES

You may opt out of receiving promotional emails from Concur by following the instructions in those emails. If you are registered on any of our sites, you may login and make certain changes to your information in your account. You may also send requests about your preferences and changes to your information by emailing [concurnews@concur.com](mailto:concurnews@concur.com). If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional emails, such as emails about your accounts or our ongoing business relations. Additionally, if you are participating in a Concur service through your employer, your employer may make changes to information on your behalf.

## CHANGES TO THIS POLICY 

Concur may change this Policy from time to time. If we make any changes to this Policy, we will change the "Last Updated" date above.

## ENFORCEMENT

If you have any questions about this Policy, please contact us at

Concur Technologies, Inc.  
18400 NE Union Hill Road  
Redmond, WA 98052  
USA  
Attention: [concurnews@concur.com](mailto:concurnews@concur.com)
